<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Presentation | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/presentation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/presentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Presentation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Presentation</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/presentation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation creating.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/%D1%81%D0%BE%D0%B7%D0%B4%D0%B0%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B5-%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%B7%D0%B5%D0%BD%D1%82%D0%B0%D1%86%D0%B8%D0%B8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/%D1%81%D0%BE%D0%B7%D0%B4%D0%B0%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B5-%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%B5%D0%B7%D0%B5%D0%BD%D1%82%D0%B0%D1%86%D0%B8%D0%B8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good presentation helps to understand the speaker, but a bad one only bores you. You know this if you defended your diploma at a university or listened to colleagues speak at a meeting. Unfortunately, there are more bad presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to distinguish a good presentation: it helps to keep the listeners&amp;rsquo; attention. In a bad presentation, everything is in a heap: the eyes scatter over bright slides, the brain tries to process the text, and at this time the speaker mumbles something about his own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make a good presentation, you do not need to be able to draw, own Photoshop and spend hours assembling slides. A good presentation is a clear presentation and a good presentation first of all. This works equally in public speeches and presentations on websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good presentation begins with questions to yourself. The most important part you can do in notepad, even without turning on the computer. First, you choose a topic, define a goal, and distribute the arguments in the right order. And only now you can open the program and search for pictures for the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rules-for-creating-a-good-presentation&#34;&gt;Rules for creating a good presentation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##1. Formulate a topic
It is difficult to listen to the interlocutor who jumps from one to another, so the presentation should have only one topic. Otherwise, it will be a long story about nothing. The topic should be narrow enough to offer a solution to the problem at the end. Narrow down the topic until the presentation cannot be presented in ten short paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is easy to identify a good topic — it suggests the structure of the speech itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-define-the-goal&#34;&gt;2. Define the goal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good presentation changes the current picture of the world. For example, people are starting to take more care of the environment or are running for a new smartphone. The goal does not have to be ambitious, the main thing is specific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good presentation goal starts with a question: what I want to change in the behavior of listeners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-think-over-the-scenario&#34;&gt;3. Think over the scenario&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of the presentation is what you want to change in the listener&amp;rsquo;s head, and the script is how you will come to these changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that you are making up a story. The listener should be intrigued, come up with an interesting hero, lead him through difficulties to a successful ending. This is the basic structure of any text and presentation. Fairy tales, movie scripts and product advertisements are based on such a structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-show-examples&#34;&gt;4. Show examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less theory means more life. Show how your product works and how people use it. Real stories of people, screenshots of programs and live photos of the product look more convincing than dry text and photos from stock photos.
##5. Alternate slides
The presentation is like a text. If the text consists of sentences of the same length and the same type, it will be boring to read. There is no rhythm. Therefore, alternate text slides and slides with images, add graphics. Sometimes you can make a joke.
##6. Tell me what to do next
A bad performance ends like this: &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s it, now the questions.&amp;rdquo; So you leave the listener alone with his thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good presentation gives clear instructions on what to do next. This is not necessarily a call to action. At the end, you can once again go through the conclusions, emphasize the main thesis or tell where to get additional information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finish with an instruction or output.
##7. Fewer colors
There should be 1-2 primary colors in the presentation. For example, for background, text and icons. Follow the selected sequence and do not change colors unnecessarily. It is quite difficult to choose colors yourself, especially if you are not a designer. If you are making a corporate presentation, use corporate colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are no branded colors, use the color matching sites. There are ready-made combinations that are nice to look at.
##8. More contrast
White on blue can look nice on your computer with a Retina screen. But if you have to show a presentation through a projector, the text will not be read. Therefore, use contrasting colors. The biggest contrast: black and white. The rest can be checked using the contrast check service.
##9. Fewer fonts
One font is enough to create a presentation. Take a modern sans-serif font: Open Sans, Roboto, PT Sans (these fonts can be used for free). These are simple fonts that are easy to read. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to check: step away from the screen and try to read the title. If it&amp;rsquo;s easy to read, you guessed it. Accents can be made by changing the font saturation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-rule-of-thirds&#34;&gt;10. Rule of thirds&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rule of creating presentations helps to arrange objects on the slide so that the eye immediately highlights the most important. Divide the slide into thirds lengthwise and across. Place significant objects at intersections. Significant objects are titles and illustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;11-the-texts-are-shorter&#34;&gt;11. The texts are shorter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One slide is one thought. This slide is easy to read and remember. If you speak publicly, it will keep the audience&amp;rsquo;s attention. Exactly how much text will be on the slide depends on the size of the audience. If a person is reading a presentation on the screen, a paragraph of text will not frighten him. If you are speaking in front of an audience of one hundred people, it will be difficult to read more than ten words on the slide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;12-calculate-how-many-slides-should-be-in-the-presentation&#34;&gt;12. Calculate how many slides should be in the presentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple rule that can be taken as a basis when creating presentations is one slide per minute. If your presentation is designed for 30 minutes, then the optimal number of slides is also 30!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;13-add-images&#34;&gt;13. Add images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photos and icons help to reveal the content, but should not replace it. If you find a beautiful photo &amp;ldquo;in the subject&amp;rdquo; that does not help to reveal the idea, do not use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;14-make-friends-with-slides&#34;&gt;14. Make friends with slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a presentation, all elements should be friends, that is, they should be of the same type. Then it is perceived easily, because it meets expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make several templates for each type of slides: a slide with text, an image, a graph. Then just duplicate the slides and change only the text and images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A presentation where the same type of elements occupy the same place on each slide looks neat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://tilda.education/articles-how-to-create-presentation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://tilda.education/articles-how-to-create-presentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
