<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Markdown | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/markdown/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Markdown</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/markdown/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markup language Markdown.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/%D1%8F%D0%B7%D1%8B%D0%BA-%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%B7%D0%BC%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%BA%D0%B8-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/%D1%8F%D0%B7%D1%8B%D0%BA-%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%B7%D0%BC%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%BA%D0%B8-markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown, or markdown, is a markup language for text documents. It allows you to create texts without using Word and other editors. The markup can be read and reproduced in any system or browser.
Markdown was created by writer and blogger John Gruber together with web activist Aaron Schwartz. They wanted to come up with the simplest and most convenient markup language with which the text can be translated into a beautifully designed form. At the same time, the text must remain readable even without bringing it to a &amp;ldquo;beautiful&amp;rdquo; appearance. This turned out to be Markdown. It was created in 2004, but the language has gained the greatest popularity now. It is supported by a variety of blogging platforms, note-taking services, CMS and even messengers. Therefore, the markdown is useful for everyone who deals with the web, from developers to bloggers.
A person writes text in any editor and adds special combinations of standard characters to it. This is a markup, it shows where the text should be bold, where it should be a title, and where a list is needed. Using symbols, you can mark up headings, text selections, and even complex structures like tables. Special converters form a ready-made document based on the markup. This is similar to using HTML, but the markdown is simpler, the text in it is more readable. Converters are either initially available in a text editor, for example in a note-taking application, or are downloaded separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-uses-the-markdown&#34;&gt;Who uses the markdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet users who communicate in messengers and write notes in services that support markup.
Developers who use markdown to write documentation for projects — they need a simple and reliable tool.
Content managers when filling sites that support markdown. Markup can also be used on web pages.
Bloggers who write longreads when they design materials for articles. Many platforms for writing texts support markdown, for example, Notion.
Writers and copywriters who need a simple tool for formatting text — markup that can be read from any device.
Enthusiasts who use markup for personal purposes: write notes and to-do lists, keep diaries or make cards for memorization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-markdown-for&#34;&gt;What is a markdown for?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick formatting of the article for translation into PDF or so that it just looks beautiful without extra effort.
Layout of a text document to be placed on the site, but without the use of HTML.
Writing documentation for the code.
Making notes in a personal digital notebook.
Writing beautiful messages in messengers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;markup-rules&#34;&gt;Markup rules&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic syntax. It is very simple: the text is &amp;ldquo;wrapped&amp;rdquo; in characters or they are placed before the line. This is how, for example, the headlines will look like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· # Header H1 (first level, for example the title of the text)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· ## Header H2 (second level, headers)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· ### H3 heading (third level, intermediate subheadings)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so on, up to the sixth-level headers with six grids in front of the line. In practice, subheadings below H3 are practically not used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In markdown, you can apply basic text formatting. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to insert a letter letter or a handwritten font, but it&amp;rsquo;s easy to highlight important areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· &lt;em&gt;Italics&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;cursive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· &lt;strong&gt;Bold text&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;bold text&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bold and underlined text&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· &amp;gt; Quote (an angle bracket is placed before each line of the quote)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· — Bulleted list item&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· 1. The first item of the numbered list&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· 2. The second item of the numbered list (and so on)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inserting materials. Markup allows you to insert different elements into the text: links and images, which will then &amp;ldquo;pull up&amp;rdquo; into the document when formatting is applied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· [link_text](any link) to insert links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· [caption to the picture] (link to the picture) to insert pictures into the text&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;· ***, — or ___ — a horizontal line for the entire line that separates part of the text from another&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if there should be an asterisk or any other &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; character in the text that can be read wrong, you need to put a backslash in front of it. For example, like this: *. Then the symbol will be displayed in the text as it should and is not considered as a markup rule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extended syntax. There is an extended version of the markdown. It&amp;rsquo;s called GFM, GitHub Flavored Markdown. It has other interesting features, for example, ~~strikethrough text ~~ wrapped in two tildes, or a `short piece of code&amp;rsquo;. A multiline code block is wrapped in three gravis above the top and below the bottom line. Like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;«`&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a line of code here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;«`&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can create tables based on vertical and horizontal line symbols. Or &amp;ldquo;to-do lists&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— [X] Completed task&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— [ ] Unfinished business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the editor supports GFM, then all such syntax elements will also be converted and will look like on a web page. It even has an emoji: you just need to insert the code of the desired smiley wrapped in colons into the text. Something like this: 😄. Emoji codes are publicly available, they can be viewed on the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-start-working-with-a-markdown&#34;&gt;How to start working with a markdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very simple: you need to install or open any editor that supports this markup and start writing. There are local editors, they need to be downloaded, and there are those that work in the browser via the Internet, as a web service. Choose any one, customize it to your needs and get started. The syntax is simple and easy to learn. It may even be that you are already partially using it: for example, in the Telegram messenger, it is the markdown that is used to format the text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to use markdown not for personal notes, but for formatting text in a blog or on a website, you need to connect a plugin with Markdown support to them. This is also not difficult, such plugins exist for many CMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is also useful for those who are planning a career as a developer. It is needed in content, in web programming, in writing documentation.
The source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.skillfactory.ru/glossary/markdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://blog.skillfactory.ru/glossary/markdown/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
